Guide to the Eero Saarinen Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Project Records, 1936-1989; 1942-1962; Series IV
  - Job 6302: Trans World Flight Center [aka TWA Terminal 5], Idlewild [now John F. Kennedy] Airport, New York, NY: Intermediate stage ramp house: Specfications, 1963 (Box 626, Folder 1660)
  - Job 6307: Trans World Flight Center [aka TWA Terminal 5], Idlewild [now John F. Kennedy] Airport, New York, NY: Intermediate stage ramp house: Drawings
    - Ammann & Whitney as-built structurals set (Box 628–629)
    - Architectural detail mylars, undated (Box 630)
    - Architectural mylars, undated (Box 631–632)
    - Architectural sepias, undated (Box 633–634)
    - Eateries: lounge, coffee shop, restaurant, undated (Box 635)
    - Electrical and mechanical plans, undated (Box 636)
    - Electrical sepias, undated (Box 637–638)
    - Expansion/ramp house, undated (Box 639–640)
    - F & B series drawings; loudspeaker, electronic sign; fuel sepias, undated (Box 641)
    - Flight Wing #1 interiors, undated (Box 642)
    - Intermediate phase "approved drawings", undated (Box 643)
    - Miscellaneous sepias, undated (Box 644)
    - Plumbing, undated (Box 645)
    - SKA drawings and site expansion, undated (Box 646)
    - Sketches: Phase III Addition, undated (Box 647)
    - Structural; Marshalling Building, undated (Box 648)
  - Job 6308: International Business Machines [IBM], Yorktown, NY: Thomas J. Watson Research Center: Drawings: Architectural mylars, structural sepias, proposed radioisotope lab addition, undated (Box 649)
  - Job 6314: Miller, J. Irwin Residence, Ontario, Canada: Drawings, undated (Box 651)
  - Job 6402: John Deere and Company Administrative Center, Moline, IL: Building #2: Drawings: Architectural and structural bid record sepias, 17 September 1966 (Box 652)
  - Job 7707: United States Embassy Chancellery, London, England: Drawings: Daylight studies; sketches, undated (Box 653)
  - Job 7708: Bell Telephone Laboratories, Holmdel, NJ: Drawings: Phase III site development and addition, undated (Box 650, Folder 1663)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified oversize project material, undated (Box 654–660)
- Audio-Visual Materials, 1956-1961; Series V
  This series contains all of the audio-visual materials in the collection. Of note in this series are the television program "CBS Accent", which shows extensive footage of the construction of Ezra Stiles and Morse Colleges at Yale University; the audio recording "Conversations Regarding the Future of Architecture", which includes speeches not only by Saarinen but also by many other architects of international renown who were prominent at mid-century; and the radio interview between Saarinen and William Hewitt, chairman of Deere & Company.
  Original audio, film, and video recordings, as well as preservation masters and duplicating masters may not be played. Readers may only play use copies. If a use copy of a particular recording does not exist, researchers must consult with the reference archivist for policies and procedures regarding the creation of duplicating master and use copies of original recordings.
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - "CBS Accent: Eero Saarinen: An Appreciation", undated
    - Original [restricted], film reel (16mm) (Box 661)
    - Duplicating master [restricted], videotape (Betamax) (Box 661-D)
    - Use Copy [also includes film footage of the TWA Terminal] (Box 661U)
  - "Conversations Regarding the Future of Architecture"[includes talks by Ernest Kump, Gordon Bunshaft, Eero Saarinen, Philip Johnson, Ludwig Mies van der Rohe, Walter Gropius, and Richard J. Neutra; sound recording edited and narrated by John Peter; produced by Reynolds Metals Co.], 1956
    - Original recording [restricted], phonodisc (LP) (Box 662)
    - Use copy [compact disc recording] (Box 662U)
  - "Eero Saarinen and Colleagues at Work", undated
    - Original [restricted], film reel (16mm) (Box 663)
    - Duplicating master [restricted], videotape (Betamax) (Box 663-D)
    - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 663U)
  - "Gene Festa describing New Haven area, Hamden, etc. Relocation", 1960 November (Box 664)
  - "General Motors: Mock-up of Pevsner's sculpture", undated
    - Original [restricted], film reel (16mm) (Box 711)
  - "KMOX Radio: Bob Hardy, KMOX Radio" [audio only], undated
    - Original [restricted], film reel (16mm) (Box 665)
    - Duplicating master [restricted], videotape (Betamax) (Box 665-D)
    - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 665U)
  - "Mexico Film I", undated
    - Original [restricted], film reel (16mm) (Box 666)
    - Duplicating master [restricted], videotape (Betamax) (Box 666-D)
    - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 666U)
  - "Mexico Film II", undated
    - Original [restricted], film reel (16mm) (Box 667)
    - Duplicating master [restricted], videotape (Betamax) (Box 667-D)
    - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 667U)
  - "NBC TV News Film: Chet Huntley Reporting: TWA", undated
    - Original [restricted], film reel (16mm) (Box 668)
    - Duplicating master [restricted], videotape (Betamax) (Box 668)
    - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 668U1)
    - Use copy, videotape (DVCAM) (Box 668U2)
  - "Radio Interview: Mr. Hewitt and Eero Saarinen", undated
    - Original [restricted], film reel (16mm) (Box 669A)
    - Original [restricted], sound reel (16mm) (Box 669B)
    - Duplicating master (audio only)[restricted], videotape (Betamax) (Box 669BD)
    - Use copy (audio only), videotape (VHS) (Box 669BU)
  - "Rough Cut WIA", undated (Box 670)
- Additional material, 1947-1966; Accession 2008-M-065
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Kevin Roche John Dinkeloo Associates, 2008.
  Arrangement
  Material is arranged by Eero Saarinen and Associates job number.
  This accession contains project files relating to a variety of Eero Saarinen and Associates projects. Files include change orders, correspondence, specifications, reports, drawings, publicity, financial material, and planning documents.
  - Job 5515: Drake University, 1947-1963 (Box 1)
    Includes Engineering Research Building, Bible College and Prayer Building change orders, Dormitories change orders, Dining Hall mural, and client files and contractor correspondence related to Jewitt Dorm #4.
  - Job 5605: Jefferson National Expansion Memorial, planning prospectus, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Job 5609: Deer & Company, specifications, equipment, 1959-1966 (Box 2)
  - Job 5610: General Motors Technical Center
    - Engineering Building reports, Circa 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    - Gas Turbine and Engineering Building, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Jobs 5703/6310: Bell Labs Holmdel Addition
    - HVAC report and toilet partitions, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - Organization and procedures book, planning requirements, and special glass experimentation, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
    - Client files, 1956-1960 (Box 6)
      - Additional material, 1957-1963 (Box 7)
    - Contractor files, 1957-1963 (Box 7)
    - Site plans, Circa 1957-1963 (Box 8)
  - Job 5707: General Motors Technical Center, Research Office Building, correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box 3)
  - Job 5710: General Motors Technical Center, Engineering Staff office, building agreement and billing, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Job 5804: Dulles Airport (Washington International)
    - Curtain wall detail drawings, errors and corrections, HVAC study, and master plan, 1958-1963 (Box 3)
    - Master plan, mobile lounges, and program information, 1958-1964 (Box 4)
    - Program information, publicity and clippings, bills and accounting, union news, and Washington office correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box 5)
  - Job 5902: North Christian Church, Sunday School program sketch, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Job 5904: Christ Lutheran Church, contract and billing, 1953-1962 (Box 5)
  - Job 6005: Athens Airport, development report, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Job 6006: Trans World Air Lines, union news, 1960 (Box 5)
  - NJN (no job number): Columbus, Indiana, development of cultural center, 1958-1961 (Box 9)
  - NJN (no job number): Report comparing gypsum roof decks and insulated steel roof decks, 1959 (Box 9)
- Additional material, Circa 1959-1969; Accession 2009-M-025
  This accession contains project files relating to the North Christian Church and Trans World Air Lines projects of Eero Saarinen and Associates. Files include drawings and specifications.
  - Job 5902: North Christian Church, architectural, structural, and mechanical drawing set, Circa 1959-1964 (Box 1)
  - Job 6307: Trans World Air Lines, Unit Terminal Building, specifications, addenda, and furnishings, 1964-1969 (Box 2)
    - Additional material, 1964-1969 (Box 3)
- Additional material, 1962-1967; Accession 2009-M-053
  Gift of Kevin Roche John Dinkeloo Associates, 2009.
  This accession contains project files relating to the North Christian Church and Vivian Beaumont Theater projects of Eero Saarinen and Associates. Files include specifications, sketches, zoning plans, and notes.
  - Job 5807: Vivian Beaumont Theater, Lincoln Center, sketches, zoning plans, and notes, 1962-1967 (Box 2)
  - Job 5902: North Christian Church, architectural specifications and bulletin, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
- Additional material, Circa 1960; Accession 2010-M-048
  Gift of Kevin Roche John Dinkeloo Associates, 2010.
  This accession contains detail drawings of the John Deere and Company Administrative Center.
  - Job 5609: John Deere and Company Administrative Center, detail drawings, Circa 1960 (Box 1)
- Additional material, Circa 1946; Accession 2010-M-121
  - Photographs of The Birmingham National Bank, Birmingham, Michigan, Circa 1946 (Box 1)
    One photograph is of existing conditions; the other is of a rendering by Saarinen Saarinen & Swanson, circa 1946.
- Additional material, 1950-1998; Accession 2011-M-003
  - Job 5004: Miller Residence, Ontario: drawings (Box 1–7)
- Additional material, 2002-2004; Accession 2011-M-052
  Gift of Jayne Merkel, 2011.
  This accession consists of recorded interviews conducted by Jayne Merkel in the course of researching her book, Eero Saarinen. Interview subjects discuss their personal and professional relationships with Eero Saarinen.
  - Recorded interview with Florence (Shu) Knoll Bassett by Jayne Merkel, 2002 December 10; 1 (Box 1)
  - Recorded interview with Frank Stanton by Jayne Merkel, 2003 April 13; 1 (Box 2)
  - Recorded interview with Phyllis Lambert by Jayne Merkel, 2003 September 24; 1 (Box 3)
  - Recorded interview with Ralph Rapson by Jayne Merkel, 2004 February 2; 1 (Box 4)
- Additional material, 1949-1959; Accession 2015-M-010
  This accession includes renderings created by Eero Saarinen and Associates employees Jay Henderson Barr (Job 4807) and Frederick T. Kubitz (Job 5206, 5503, 5512, 5604, and the unnumbered R.J. Reynolds Research Facility), the latter of whom worked as an architectural designer at the firm from 1955 to 1960.
  - Job 4807: General Motors Technical Center, Warren, MI
    - Renderings (photographs), Circa 1949 - circa 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Renderings (oversize), 1949 (Folder 2)
  - Job 5206: Drake University, Des Moines, IA: Women's Dormitory, Circa 1953 - circa 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Job 5503: United States Embassy, Oslo, Norway, Circa 1952 - circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Job 5512: Greenwich Railroad Station, Greenwich, CT, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Job 5604: International Business Machines [IBM], Rochester, MN, Circa 1957 - circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Job 5902: North Christian Church, Columbus, IN, Circa 1959 - circa 1960 (Folder 2)
  - NJN (no job number): R.J. Reynolds Research Facility, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional material, 1963-1978; Accession 2015-M-047; 3
  Gift of Kevin Roche John Dinkeloo Associates, 2015.
  This accession contains drawings relating to the Bell Telephone Laboratories project (Holmdel, NJ) of Eero Saarinen and Associates, which comprised several job numbers (5703, 6102, 6310, and 7708).
  - Job 5703: Bell Telephone Laboratories, index sheet, planting plans, and detail drawings, Undated (Box 1)
  - Job 6102: Bell Telephone Laboratories, sections and roof plan, Undated (Box 1)
  - Job 6310: Bell Telephone Laboratories, planting plans and details, 1963-1978 (Box 1)